Eren Kalinsazlioglu

eren@enpoi.com | +49 17659532268 | Niedenstein, Germany | Website | YouTube | Github

About me

I have passion and an aptitude for innovation, creative problem-solving, and analytical thinking. Theoretical and practical knowledge of electronics, mechanics, and software development processes are my strengths. I started making paper models myself. I was very successful. Then I tried to create my own designs on the computer and make them yourself. I started to be interested in 3D printers and participated in various activities on this subject. When I came to Germany, I started to concentrate on animation, film making and game development. I am a continuous learner who loves and stays in tune with the latest technology. My future plans are to combine all this knowledge I have learned and develop projects. Looking forward to making new machines and inventions.

Skills

- Personal skills: Problem Solving | Generating new ideas | Innovative | Honesty | Communication |
 Leadership | Relationship Building | Collaboration | Focused | Motivation
- Computer Experience: 3D modeling Solidworks | Sketchup | Blender | Unreal Engine | Unity |
 Character Creator 3.0 | Blueprint Visual Scripting (Blender, Unreal Engine) |
 | 3D Printing Software Simplify3D | Lightburn | Arduino | VS Code | Platform IO | Git/GitHub | Marlin |
 | Delphi | JavaScript | C/C++ | Python | Scratch | MS Office | GSuite | OBS Studio | Oracle VirtualBox |
 | Inkscape | Adobe Products | WinDirStat | Oculus Quest | Goanimate | PowToon | Calibre | Davinci Resolve

Languages

Turkish (Native) | English (B2) | German (B2)

Education

Beruf. Gymnasium | Max-Eyth-Schule | Kassel, Germany | Sep 2019 – continues Gymnasium | Dr.-Georg-August-Zinn-Schule | Gudensberg, Germany | Sep 2019 – July 2022 Middle School | Ankara Vadi Collage | Ankara, Turkey | Sep 2018 - Jun 2019 Middle School | Rotary Yeşiltepe | Ankara, Turkey | Sep 2016 - Jun 2018 Middle School | Batikent Samanyolu Collage | Ankara, Turkey | Sep 2014 - Jun 2016 Elementary school | Rotary Yeşiltepe | Ankara, Turkey | Sep 2011 - Jun 2014

Experience

Lingua Guide | Project | Germany | 01.12.2023

- Developed "Lingua Guide," an Al-powered German language learning chatbot.
- Created and managed a personal Kickstarter campaign for the <u>Lingua Guide project</u>.
- Created a personalized and adaptive user interface for enhanced learning experiences.
- Implemented real-time interactive features for practical conversation practice.
- Integrated contextual learning scenarios for realistic language use.
- Enabled multilingual support for wider accessibility.
- Incorporated cultural insights into the learning material.
- Pioneered a free, open-source solution in educational technology.
- Applied personal experiences in language learning to address common challenges.

Hammertime | Praktikum | Germany | 10.01.2022 - 21.01.2022

- An Egg Drawing Machine was built and documented.
- New skills related to chip programming have been developed and the functions of different chips have been learned.
- Using the ESP32 Chip, a strip led working over the Internet was made.
- T-shirt and glass printing was learned.
- It was learned how the Industrial Laser works and how it is used, and some demos were made.
- The components of the chips were learned and repaired by installing the bootloader on Arduino Mainboards.
- Analyzed the broken 3D printers and where they are causing problems.

Onmuş Turbo | Praktikum | Turkey | 15.06.2019 - 15.08.2019

- Gained information about Car Turbo repair.
- The elements that make up the turbo have been learned.
- Learned how to do stock management.
- It has been learned how the Turbo is calibrated.
- Sandblasting, cleaning, sanding and assembly have been learned

7den70e Family Club | Turkey | 2018

- I made presentations about 3D printers at the Family Club and Fairs
- www.7den70e.net/7den70eblog

Ideal Technology | Praktikum | Turkey | 2016

- 3D printers were manufactured and repaired.
- Solidworks learned while designing new 3D printers.
- 3D printed products and Parts were sold.

Certification & Awards

Germany 2023
Germany 2023
Germany 2022
Germany 2021
Germany 2021
Germany 2020
Turkey 2019
Turkey 2018
Turkey 2017
Turkey 2016
Turkey 2014

Volunteer Experience

ABP Academic Education | Mentoring | Germany | (from 01.06.2021)

• I provide mentoring and education to primary school children at the ABP Academic Education Association.